Guide to the Ingram Olkin papers SC1221
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH_2017_266
  - Papers
    - Olkin - "Combining Independent Studies Based on Correlation Mea…., 1981 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Marsaglia -Olkin (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Shafer - Problem, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - unlabeled, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - NSF - Meta-Analysis, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Corr revisited (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Copss History, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Bridges - Scool of Education, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Mary Goldstein Proposal, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Organics, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Organics, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Dena, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - n Estimators (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - SRI, 1985 Dec 24 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - SRI, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - NSF Moore - Olkin (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Papers, proposals, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Bivariate Binomial math notes (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Chapter 4 -Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Chapter 5 - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Chapter 6 - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Chapter 7 - Kendall/ Olkin (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Appendix (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Chapter 8 - Kendall/Olkin, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Chapter 2 - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Chapter 3 - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Clustering - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Chapter 9 - Kendall/Olkin, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - non-parametric test - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Chapter 1 - Kendall/Olkin, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Biserial Correlations - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Multiple Correlations - Kendall/Olkin (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Biblio - Independence of Forms (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - An Inequality for a Sum of Forms (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Chapter 11 - Kendall/Olkin, 1981 Jan (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography - Kendall/Olkin, 1980 Aug (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Katz- Olkin Configurations (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 10 - Kendall/Olkin (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - majorizations - talks (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Majorization talk, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Slides for Matrix Theory and Majorization talk (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Marcel Dekker, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Majorization - transparencies (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Meta-Analysis: A Quantitative Approach to Research Integration in the Medical and Health Sciences, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Doing and Understanding Meta-Analysis and not being misled by the results, 1997 Sep 25 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Multiple comparisons (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Moler correspondence, Lancer correspondence, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - NSF misc. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - pain, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Olkin Shepp (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - NSF Women, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - NSF, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Cornell Eng. Report on Women (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Savage - Olkin Correspondence, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence - O Thro, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence K, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence - W Thro, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence - R Thro, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Bergstrom, Harald, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence - L Thro, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Savage - Olkin Correspondence, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Problems and Misinterpretations in Published Meta-Analysis, 2007 Apr (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Drug Information Association, 1999 Jun 27 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Meta-Analysis papers, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Probability, Statistics papers (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - ASA - Toronto, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Presentation slideshows, 2005-2013 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Statesmanship, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Tufts, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Publications, proposals (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Modeling, Data, handwritten notes (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - General Multivariate (misc), 1955 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Siotani - Olkin Shrikhande-Olkin, 1964 Oct - Jan (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - unlabeled (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence binder contents (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - math notes (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Notes on the theory of multivariate, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - math notes (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Meteor transparencies, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Olkin/Woodworth: correlation problem, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Olkin, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Olkin Matrix (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Theory of Selected Methods of Finite Matrix Inversion and Decomposition, 1951-1954 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - photos, postcards (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Olkin, I. Special Topics in Matrix Theory and Inequalities copy 2, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Matrix Theory Course (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - math notes (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Latvia (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Biography and Appreciation of Ingram Olkin (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - misc, 2004-2011 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - News/publication, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - American Educational Research Association Fellow award, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Linear alg. In mult analysis (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - On Closet Normal Matrices by Robert L. Causey Technical Report CS10, 1964 Jun 30 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - PhD aid req., 1975-1976 Fall (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Workshop statistics for journalists, 2002 Nov 7-8 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Publications (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Statistics, lecture 2, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - The Biserial and Point Correlation Coefficients R.F. Tate (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - handwritten notes (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Publications, 1989-2004 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - JSM Professional Development Program CE 18C: Meta-Analysis: Combining the results of Multiple Studies, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence- N thro, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence - S thro, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence - P thro, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence - T thro, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence - J thro, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence - M Thro, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence - H Thro, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - NSF (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Systematic Review meta-analysis (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Book review (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Outline for Revision of Hedges + Olkin Book on Meta-Analysis (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Heterogeneity, math notes (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Publications, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - powerpoint presentation slides (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Are Guidelines Following Guidelines?, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Methods for Combining slideshow (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Elein Allen Transparencies (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - MAL-MAP (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - History - MA transparencies (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Single Experiment (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Evidence Based medicine slideshow (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Consistency, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - misc. slideshow (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - EPA Report, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Intro info explosion (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Early Clinical Trial (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - S P RUTRAP Bulletins, 1959 Nov 5 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - IMS Committee on Russian Translations, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - IMS Russian Translation, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Visiting Lectures Program Comm. -COPSS, 1989-1990 Jul (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - History of COPSS, 1972 Oct (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - IMS - Correspondence Treasurer, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - AAAS Coordinating Comm. -COPSS, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Charts + By-laws Comm.- COPSS, 1991-1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - COPSS Manual, 1994-1997 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - COPSS - Snedecor/Scott Award, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - S A Rutrap, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Multuvariate analysis (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Graphics, 1961-1993 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Olkin - Tech. reports and publications, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - COPLOT transparency (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Corr - Dwyer, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - presentation slides, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - 70th Anniversary of the Distribution of Random Matrices, 2000 Jul 17-20 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Experts Probability Models, 2005 Jan 31 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - M-O talk NYU models for life distributions, 1998 Apr (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Correlation and Chi-Square test J. Wolfowitz (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Probability Inference J. Wolfowitz (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Student Class notes (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Hotelling, Harold, 1971 Jul (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Multivariate Analysis: Overview, 2000 Dec 12 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Rivoshima Talk (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Lehmann notes (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - SIMS, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - SIMS current, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Olkin - Faculty Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - notebook (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Mixtures involving Poisson and Bernoulli Distributions, 1983 Apr (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Numerical analysis (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - math notes (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Iowa State College correspondence, math notes, 1956 Oct 30 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - misc., 1961 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare Grant Application, 1976 Jun 28 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Sponsored Project Proposal Routing Sheet, 1992 Feb 5 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Proposal of Research Grant in Mathematical Methods in Educational Research, 1975-1977 Jan - Dec (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Stanford Statistics, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Proposal for Workshop in Statistical inference (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Interim Report of the Quantitative Methods, 1990 May (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Schonberg correspondence, 1986 Jan 6 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Biographical information, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Publications, 1978-2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1950-2000 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Math/Statistics notes (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Talk for Storrs, 1997 Apr 24 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - National Security Agency proposal, MSU report, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Speech notes (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Pamphlets, speaker announcement flyers, 1989-1996 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Publications, 1978-1996 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Statistics, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Course review evaluations, 1993-2003 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Hedges draft copy of book, 2000 Sep 7 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Hedges - Olkin book (binder contents), 2000 Jan 31 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Hedges - Olkin book chapters 8-13 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Hedges - Olkin book Chapter 1-7 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Chapter 9-13 binder contents (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Hedges - Olkin Chapters 8-14 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Hedges-Olkin book chapters 1-7 (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Hedges-Olkin book chapters 1-7 (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Hedges-Olkin binder contents (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Hedges- Olkin binder contents (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Large texts Storrs, 1997 Apr 24 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Transparencies talk for Press, symposium, 2005 May (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Diagnostic with p-values transparencies (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - SRSM talk - hetero - transparencies (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Goals Issues Prof. Gary Simon (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - intro transparencies (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Probability Models for nonnegative random variables, 2004 Dec 8 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - I2 vs Q, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Life Distributions and Meta-Analysis Olkin (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - workshop flyer (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - math, statistics notes (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Presentation slideshows, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - correspondence, 1984-2012 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Statistics for Journalists, 2002 Nov 7-8 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Structure of Life Distributions, 2013 May 13 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Life Distributions and Meta-Analysis, 2007 Jul (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - SMDM short course #2, 2007 Oct 21 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Transparencies for AERA Discussion, 2006 Apr (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - SCHATT BRJBB Health Policy Poland Talk (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Probability Models for nonnegative random variables, 2004 Dec 8 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - National Security Agency proposal, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Biography, meeting minutes (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - handwritten notes (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Publications, 1989-2005 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Publications, 1985-1997 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Experts (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - transparencies Greece (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Probability Models for nonnegative random variables, 2004 Mar 22-25 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - M.O- Talk on Book (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Multivariate Analysis Workshop, 2006 Aug 28-29 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Cambridge Transparencies talk, 2006 Aug (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Neuchatel handouts, 2006 Jun (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Neuchatel (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Nonparametric p-values slideshow (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - ETS talk Biv. Dist. Modeling (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - End of meta-talk reporting cardinal numbers (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Measures of discrep. (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Goals Issues, conclusions slideshow (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - A Single Experiment, Meta-Analysis slideshow (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Meta-Analysis, 2007 Jun (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Talk for Israel, 2006 Dec (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - P-values (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - meta-analysis handwritten notes (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - publications, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - misc. pamphlet (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Publication reprints, 1946-1968 (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - booklets, 1967-2004 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Audiovisual Materials
    - Last Lecture in Sequoia Hall Charles Stein Prof. Emeritus, Statistics, 1996 Mar 19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - De Montfort University Graduation Ceremony, 1997; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Gertrude M. Cox Building Dedication, Symposium and Dinner Tape 1 of 2, 1999 Sep 9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Gertrude M. Cox Building Dedication, Symposium and Dinner Tape 2 of 2, 1999 Sep 9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Lecture on Meta-Analysis Harrisburg copy, 1992 Oct 16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - An Overview of Meta-Analysis with Ingram Olkin, 1992 Apr 13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - The History and Development of Meta-Analysis, Ingram Olkin, 58 min. A Conversation with Ingram Olkin, 1997 May 5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - The History and Development of Meta-Analysis, Ingram Olkin, 58 min. A Conversation with Ingram Olkin, 1997 May 5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - UH vs. UCLA Shavelron starring in Row 1 (starts about halfway in), 1997 Jan 25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Ingram Olkin Statistics, 1984 Aug 2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - "Proschan Festivities" Tape 2 Dept of Statistics, 1993 Dec 7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - "Proschan Festivities" Tape 1 Dept of Statistics, 1993 Dec 6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Graduation Leicester Honorary Degree I. Olkin, 1997 Jul; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 14)
    - NZSA Conference, 2010; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 14)
    - IWMS, 2004; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 14)
    - History of Convexity Djura Panic, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 14)
    - Old, 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 14)
    - olkin file on Sensitivity (Saner), 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 14)
    - Statistics Pictures Macintosh/Tiff (New Sequoia) open these files from within a graphical software program, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 14)
    - Dad lecturing, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 9, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 7, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - Norelco, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 5, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 6, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - Do First, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 3, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - Lower Priority than class materials, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 8, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 2, 1983 Jul 28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 1, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
    - 5-5 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)